<Document>
  # Space Stories - Marine Corps Game Rules

  The rules in this section and the in-game guide are primary and take priority over all other sources, including Discord and the Wiki.

  ## Recent Changes (28.10.2025)
  - [textlink="Rule 2: Roleplay" link="STRolePlay"] has been reworked and expanded — new sections added about IC communication, toxicity, awards, and Xenomorph behavior. This rule now establishes overall roleplay standards for all players on the server.
  - [textlink="Rule 3: Metagaming and Metacommunication" link="STMetagamingMetacommunication"] completely rewritten, with new violation examples and clarified faction knowledge, Xenomorph behavior, and voice-chat teaching allowances.
  - [textlink="Rule 4: ERP" link="STERP"] clarified that punishment depends on context and intent; minor IC profanity is not a violation.
  - [textlink="Rule 5: Bug Abuse and Unfair Play" link="STBuggingFoulPlay"] expanded violation list — now includes intentional glitching and visual bug abuse even “just for fun,” with clarified allowed exceptions.
  - [textlink="Rule 7: Play Your Role" link="STPlayYourRole"] fully reworked — role responsibility tiers and proper exit procedures added. This rule now defines core behavioral expectations and duty obligations within character roles.
  - [textlink="Rule 8: Character Names" link="STCharacterNames"] clarified naming requirements, with new restrictions on copying characters and CAPS-style nicknames.

  The remaining rules have not been changed.

  ## Administrative decisions are final.
  - Rules are applied according to their intent. It is impossible to list every violation example; therefore enforcement depends on administrative interpretation of the rule’s meaning.
  - Administrators may resolve rule violations using in-game consequences for characters at their discretion. This does not apply to zero-tolerance rules.
  - You may submit an appeal to head staff if you believe a decision was incorrect.

  ## General Information
  Disabling, ignoring, or refusing to answer an admin’s ahelp will result in a ban that is only appealable.
  This is to prevent players from avoiding consequences. If you need to leave urgently, inform us — this will be taken into account when reviewing an appeal.

  All rules below apply at all times, including between rounds.

  ## Core Rules
  These are the primary Space Stories - Marine Corps rules. Click on them for detailed information.
  - [textlink="Rule 0: Community Expectations" link="STCommunityExpectations"]
  - [textlink="Rule 1: Grief" link="STGrief"]
  - [textlink="Rule 2: Roleplay" link="STRolePlay"]
  - [textlink="Rule 3: Metagaming and Metacommunication" link="STMetagamingMetacommunication"]
  - [textlink="Rule 4: ERP" link="STERP"]
  - [textlink="Rule 5: Bug Abuse and Unfair Play" link="STBuggingFoulPlay"]
  - [textlink="Rule 6: Ban Evasion and Multi-Accounts" link="STBypassBlockingMultiAccounts"]
  - [textlink="Rule 7: Play Your Role" link="STPlayYourRole"]
  - [textlink="Rule 8: Character Names" link="STCharacterNames"]
  - [textlink="Rule 9: Use of Lethal Force" link="STUseOfLethalForce"]
  - [textlink="Rule 10: Military Law and Mutinies" link="STMilitaryLawMutinies"]
</Document>
