<Document>
  # Rule 0: Community Expectations
  The administrator reserves the right to disregard or adjust the application of specific rules if this is necessary for the benefit of the current round, the server, or the community as a whole. Any use of this rule requires notifying and coordinating with the highest-ranking administrator currently online. Responsibility for the consequences of such decisions lies entirely with the administrator who applied the rule.

  The application of rules depends on administrative interpretation, as not all violations can be clearly documented in writing.

  If an administrator gives instructions or makes a decision, you are expected to respect and follow it without arguing. If you disagree, you may submit an appeal through the forum, Discord, or directly to the administrator’s superior after the round has ended. Arguing with staff may result in punishment. Administrators are volunteers, and toxicity or hostility towards them will not be tolerated.

  General conduct expectations for all members of the community. Unless stated otherwise, these rules apply everywhere:
  - Treat others with respect.
  - Do not make threats (even as a joke) outside of in-character context (OOC).
  - Use common sense to determine whether your actions are appropriate.
  - This list is not exhaustive; it highlights only key points.

  ## Racism and Intolerance
  - OOC insults on the server are not tolerated and may result in bans.
  - Any form of racism is strictly prohibited.
  - Sexism and extremist behavior are not allowed.
  - Usernames containing racist, sexist, or otherwise offensive elements may be prohibited at the discretion of the administration.

  ## Stereotypes
  - Playing a character based on a stereotype is allowed, but creating a character who is a racial, religious, or cultural caricature is not.
  - The head administration or the highest-ranking administrator online reserves the right to determine which stereotypes are considered offensive.
</Document>
